More than Five years' experience in the field of Computer software implementation, hardware and network. well aware of different financial accounting systems (Microsoft Dynamics AX, Cosmo Soft, CMS) and all media types of Networking. Strong Administrative abilities.

#### Skills

Administrative Skills

Communication Skills

Local Area Networks

Software implementation

SOL

#### Education

#### NCBA&F

BS(CS) | Lahore 2017 |

#### BISE.

FSC. | FSD 2012 |

#### **BISE Faisalabad**

Metric | Faisalabad 2010 |

# Certifications

**ONE Trust** 

Coursera

### CCNA

## PC Networking

Word Press (E-Rozgar)

#### **Industries**

Information Technology

# Professional Experience | 5 Years

### IT Officer

Sharif Group of Companies | Chiniot, Pakistan Feb 2023 - Present

- Management and Administrator of CPS (Cane Procurement System by Oracle soft).
- Management and Support ERP (Financial Accounting System By EBS).
- Working on FortiGate firewall for secure internet services.
- Installation of new database Servers.
- Define and implement of Securities policies.
- Upgrade Network infrastructure 100 MB to 1G with Fiber Media.

### System Support Engineer

ALMOIZ Industries | Piplan Mianwali, Pakistan Oct 2021 - Jan 2023

- · Configuration & Handling Sophos firewall.
- · Handling of all Administrative and Departmental Issues.
- · Provide fully Backend Support for Smooth Running Financial Accounting System Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 ERP System.
- · Implementation of Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 ERP new modules.
- · Handling and Installation of Database Server and Domain Controller.
- · Control and implement Sugar Cane software.
- · Implementation and provide Support of Mobile Apps (Android applications.) Like ELP Tracking, E-Survey and Depo management Etc.
- · Handling Sophos firewall.
- · Define and implement of Securities policies.
- · Monitoring, Installation, Troubleshooting & Control Errors of Network.
- · Cisco Router Configurations.
- · wised knowledge Installation and troubleshooting of IP Camera's.

### **IT** Engineer

Madina Group of Industries. | Faisalabad, Pakistan

Ian 2019 - Oct 2021

- Control all staff of IT section, including all software management.
- Handling and Installation of Database Server and Domain Controller.
- Responsible for smoothly running of Fiber and STP Network.
- 24 hours available for troubleshooting and any IT related problem
- During crushing period
- Installation, Troubleshooting & Control Errors of Network.
- (U.T.P, Wireless and Fiber optic)
- Define and implement of Network Securities policies.
- Control and implement Sugar Cane software.
- Installation and troubleshooting of IP Camera's.Installation
- and Trouble CCTV Cameras.
- Preparation of reports for Head office & another Department.
- Collect the information about new technology and make possible to implement

### **Network Operation Monitoring Officer**

AL-Fazal Engineer Lahore

Aug 2018 - Dec 2016

- · Installing and Configuring computer hardware, Software and Operating System.
- · Responsible for the provision and development of IT infrastructure also CCTV Installation.



Sitara Spinning Mills | Pakistan

- · Handling and Installation of Database Server and Domain Controller.
- · Define and implement of Network Securities policies.
- $\cdot$  Installation, Troubleshooting & Control Errors of Network.

(U.T.P, Wireless and Fiber optic)

- · Monitoring and trouble Shooting of Video conferencing system.
- · Installation and troubleshooting of IP Camera's.
- · Installation and Trouble CCTV Cameras.
- · Preparation of reports for Headoffice & other Department.
- $\cdot$  Collect the information about new technology and make possible to implement

### Management Trainee Officer

Sitara Spinning Mills | Pakistan

- · Installation of Database Server and Domain Controller.
- · Implement of Network Securities policies.
- $\cdot$  Maintain the users, Groups and Computers from domain controller.
- · Surfing of internet and check the updates about network.
- $\cdot$  Supervision of Computerized Token & Weighbridge.
- · Assist to System Analyst for Data entry, System & Reports Designing.

## Languages

Urdu - Native

English - Medium

Saraiki - Medium